In this lecture, I'm going to show you a demo of the Amazon
Bedrock Knowledge Base.
So we're going to build an e-learning app.
And this is the architecture we had discussed earlier.
So we're going to follow this architecture.
So the first thing we're going to do is we're
going to select the data source.
And in our case, the data source is going to be S3 bucket.
From the data perspective, we're going
to have a PDF document of the Amazon Bedrock User Guide,
which we are going to upload to S3 bucket.
So this is going to be our PDF.
It's basically a user guide of Amazon Bedrock.
And it has about 200 pages.
So when the end user makes a query,
the Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Base is going
to refer to this particular document
to retrieve and generate an answer.
So I'm on the AWS console now.
Remember, you cannot create a Bedrock Knowledge Base
through root user.
You need to create an IAM user.
So let me just search for IAM.
And then I'll just click on IAM.
And here, just click on the user.
And just click on create user.
And then you can just give it any name.
So let me just say demo one.
And then I'll just click on this.
And I want to create an IAM user.
And you can just auto generate password.
Then let me just click on next.
And here, you have to do permissions.
So I can say attach policies directly.
Search for the policy here.
And I'll just say admin access.
Just click on this admin access.
And then just click on next.
And just click on create user.
So I'll just copy this.
Maybe go to a new incognito window
and just open it from here.
Now I'll just copy this user name.
And then just provide the user name here.
So I'll just copy this password.
And let me just provide the password.
And then just sign in.
OK, now I'm on the AWS console.
So the first thing we have to do is
we have to create an S3 bucket, which
will be our data source.
So let me just click here.
Just make sure you're in the US East one.
So I'll just go to North Virginia and US East one.
OK, now I have this S3 bucket open again here as well.
Let me just change it to North Virginia.
Now I'm in the North Virginia region.
Let me just click on this create bucket.
And let's just give this bucket a name.
So I'll just say demo bedrock kb01 just to make it unique.
And then let me just say create bucket.
OK, now this bucket has been created.
Let me just click on view details.
Now you hear you can upload our PDF document,
which is in our case bedrock user guide.
But you can upload any document that you
want our users to refer for e learning.
So I'll just drop it here.
And let me just say upload OK.
Now our document has been uploaded.
So let me just close this.
And let me just go back to the console.
And here now I will just search for bedrock.
OK, I'll just click on Amazon bedrock.
Now I'm on the Amazon bedrock service.
So if you just scroll down under build,
I can see knowledge basis.
So let me just click on this.
And I'll scroll down and here I have create.
So I can just click on this create.
And you'll see we have unstructured data,
knowledge basis, vector store, Kendra, Gen A index.
We have structured data, structured data store.
So since we have a PDF document, it's
going to be unstructured data.
And in our case, let's go with this knowledge
base with vector store.
So we're going to look at all of these in the later section.
But for now, let's just go with this knowledge
basis vector store.
OK, now we have to provide the name here.
Maybe I'll just go with the same name
that we had given to the S3 bucket,
which is demo bedrock KB01.
And you can provide description if you may like.
But I'll just keep it blank.
It's optional.
Next, we have the IM permissions.
Certain permissions are necessary to access other services
or perform actions in order to create this resource.
For more information, see the service role for Amazon bedrock.
So we're going to let Amazon bedrock create the service
room.
Amazon bedrock service might need access to other services
like S3 bucket, maybe a vector store and so on.
So we'll let it create the service room.
Next, we have to choose the data source.
So if you just go here in our architecture diagram,
we had to create the data source.
And then we had to add the data.
So we already created the S3 bucket.
And then we have added the PDF document here.
Here, I have multiple options.
So I can select maybe Amazon S3.
Maybe I can have a web crawler.
So maybe our e-learning user wants some information
from the internet.
So our knowledge base can go and crawl some data
and then answer his queries.
So you can also have a custom data source.
You can have confluence, sales force, SharePoint.
So there are multiple options.
For our case, we'll just go with S3 bucket.
So let me just click on S3 bucket.
Then you can add some tags.
If you like, then you can also add some log deliveries,
application logs.
It's an optional.
And we're going to take a look at this in the next few
lectures.
Now, let me just click on next.
And here, you can see, we have this data source name.
So it's auto generated.
So I'll leave it as it is.
Then data source location.
So this AWS account, yeah, this data source S3 bucket
is in this account.
Now we have to give the link of the S3 bucket.
So I'll just click on browse.
And I can just search from creation date and creation date.
So this is the demo bedrock KV01 bucket we had created.
So I'm just going to click on this.
And I'll say choose.
So next, you can also add customer managed KMS key for S3 data.
So if you want to encrypt the data at rest,
then you can use KMS key for that.
So I'm not going to do that.
So let me just continue.
So next is the parsing strategy.
Now we have three options.
We have the Amazon bedrock default parser.
Now if the data in your data source is like text documents,
word, Excel, HTML, then you select this parsing strategy.
But if you have, let's say images, audio, and videos,
then you select the Amazon bedrock data automation as parser.
And then if you have PDFs, images, and then also structure
document tables and forms or visual rich document,
then you select foundation model as a parser.
So now we are done with step one.
Now if you look at this step two, we have this data chunking strategy.
So now if I just go back here, you can see the chunking strategy.
So chunking breaks down the text into smaller segments before embeddings.
There are multiple ways and you can break down, let's say in our case,
we have the 200 page documents into smaller chunks.
So then our embedding model can create vector embeddings.
And we're going to deep dive into each of them a little later.
But for now, just remember, there are multiple strategies for chunking.
So we'll just go with the default one.
OK, then you also have this transformation function.
So now let's say you need to apply some transformation rules, et cetera.
Then you can write your lambda function.
That is going to do that processing of the documents.
OK, now I'm just going to click on next.
Now if I go to the architecture, you can see our third step is embedding model.
So we have to select the embedding model.
So if I just click on the select embedding model,
so you can see we have two model service providers, Amazon and Coheer.
So let me just click on Amazon and then here, you can select the model.
So you have Amazon, no multimodal embeddings.
So multimodal means it can handle both text and images, et cetera.
Then we have the Titan embeddings model and we have the Titan text embedding model,
which can only handle text.
So let me just select this Titan text embeddings V2.
And let me just do apply.
OK, now if I go back to the architecture or fourth step is selecting the vector database.
So that's what we're going to do.
And you can see vector store type.
So there are multiple vector store types that Amazon bedrock provides by default.
So now we have the vector store here.
So here you have two options, quick create a new vector store.
So if you have existing vector store, you can select this.
Otherwise, you can select the quick create new vector store.
And if I just click on this, it will give me some options.
So you have open search serverless, Amazon S3 vectors, Amazon Aurora Postgres, SQL Server.
And then we have the Amazon Neptune analytics.
So I'm just going to select this Amazon S3 vector because it's much cheaper compared to the other vector stores.
So please remember, when you create a better knowledge, especially when you select the vector store,
let's say if you select open search, there's going to be a per hour charge and a repeat per hour charge.
So which is about 50 cents for S3 vectors, it's going to be much lesser.
But if you're following along, make sure you delete the better knowledge basis.
OK, now I just click on Amazon S3 vector, and then I'll just click on next.
And then you are on this review and create page.
And now I'm just going to say create knowledge base.
So it's going to take a few minutes to create the knowledge base.
So you can see it's in the process of creating the better knowledge base.
So I just made it a few minutes and you can see our knowledge base has been created now.
Now if you just scroll down, you can see the data source here.
And if you see here, last sync, so there is no sync that has been done,
which means that no vector embeddings for our data source have been created.
So what we need to do is we just need to click on this and then just click on sync.
Again, it's going to take a few minutes to complete the sync.
So we'll just wait till the sync is complete.
OK, now our sync is complete and if you just see here, it shows last sync is right now.
Now if I just click on this test knowledge base, so let me just do that.
And here you can see some configurations here.
So the first one is retrieval and response generation.
So remember, there are two APIs provided by better knowledge base.
One is retrieve only and then we have retrieve and response generation.
So retrieve only means it's only going to retrieve the vector embeddings from the vector store.
But it's not going to generate an answer.
And then you have retrieval and response generation,
which means that it's going to retrieve the vector embeddings.
And then also it's going to generate the knowledge base from the large language model that we use.
OK, so I'm just going to select retrieve only for now so that I can show you.
OK, so I'm just going to pose a question now and then we're going to take a look at the other configurations a little later.
So I'll say what is Amazon bedrock?
And let me just pose this question.
So you can see it has retrieved only the chunks from the vector store for the PDF document that we had uploaded.
But it's not generated an answer.
Now if I just cancel this and let me select this retrieval and response generation.
So if I just click on this, I have to select the foundation model.
So if I just go to the architecture, you can see here the six step was selecting the large language model.
So I can just select a model here.
Let me say Amazon and let me say no up to and just to a select now if I just ask the same question.
Let me just click here and you will see it will give a full flushed answer.
And you can see here based on the retrieve result Amazon bedrock is a fully managed service that makes base models.
And then it gives some more details and here here are some citations.
So if I just click on any of the citations, it will show me from where it is getting this answer.
And this is the Amazon bedrock user guide that we had uploaded.
Okay, now you can see here there's another option called as details.
And if I just click on these details, so what you can see here is the various chunks that it has retrieved.
So you have the source chunk one and then we have the source chunk two, source chunk three and so on.
So now if you see in the architecture, what we had earlier discussed was when the user poses this question,
it will pass through text embedding model, then it's going to do a similarity search and retrieve the context chunks,
which match in this vector database corresponding to this user question embeddings.
And those are these chunks that have been retrieved that you can see here.
So here you can see some of the configurations we have the guard rail.
And if you just click on this, you'll be able to see all the guard rails that you have created.
And if you want to select one, you can do that.
So guard rail version, then you have the re ranking model.
So you can select any re ranking model.
So right now it only seems to be supporting cohere.
So you have the re rank 3.5.
So what re ranker model does is enables a re ranker model to rescore the relevance of retrieved
source chunks and override the vector database relevance ranking.
So you can see it has retrieved multiple chunks.
So when we use a re ranking model, it's going to re rank these chunks based on the relevance.
And we're going to discuss about re ranking models a little later.
And then if I just continue to scroll down, so here are some other configuration
parameters related to generation.
Like if you want to reset the model inference parameters,
generation prompt, orchestration prompt, and so on, you can do that.
Okay, so that's pretty much it from the demo.
Hope you liked the demo.
I'll see you in the next lecture.
Thank you.